Kartik Anand

Collaborative professional with ~3 years of experience in the financial services industry. Excellent problem-solving skills that help drive results in an extremely fast-paced environment. Background in software development and analytics. Strategic and decisive thinker with strong communication skills and interpersonal abilities.





anandkartik97@gmail.com



9999665148



New Delhi, India



in linkedin.com/in/kartik-anand-44323312a

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analytics Associate NatWest Group

Gurugram India

- Developed spreadsheet analyzer tool that retrieves cellular information from EUDAs and uses visualizations to highlight the areas subject to higher risks
- Text analytics on historic audit reports for readability, sentiment & wordcloud analysis aiding audit team validate the adherence of audit report ratings
- Extracted and identified articles requiring IA coverage from regulatory websites using Python. Built a Flask app with dynamic visuals allowing senior management to view and modify the underlying data
- Developed a negative news bot to fetch news articles and perform sentiment analysis to classify negative articles

Technology Analyst - C10

Citicorp Services India Pvt. Ltd.

08/2020 - 11/2021

Pune, India

- · Automated the outbound flow for SFTR Regulatory Reporting by using Apache Camel routing framework to generate and transfer the outbound files
- Streamlined and optimized the ETL pipeline catering to a huge volume of data (50+ GB daily) and stored it in 3 different data stores: Mongo, Elastic and Impala saving 2+ hours of efforts daily
- Created Tableau dashboard to increase the acceptance rates (ack-nack ratio) by 10% and performed time series analysis of ACKs/NACKs/Exceptions

Technology Analyst - C09

Citicorp Services India Pvt. Ltd.

08/2019 - 07/2020

- · As a part of Client Connectivity Team, Developed microservices using Java for OneConnect which is a low latency global order routing platform
- Designed and implemented Risk & Compliance Checks and enhanced the Filter Module for OneView

Data Science and Analytics Intern

Royal Bank of Scotland

05/2018 - 07/2018

Gurugram, India

 Conceptualized and delivered 2 self-service automated tools written in Python that reduced the data validation TAT by 80%

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (Software Engineering)

Delhi Technological University

2015 - 2019

8.71 CGPA (First Division)

Class XII

Salwan Public School, New Delhi

2014 - 2015

96.6% (School Topper)

Class X

Salwan Public School, New Delhi

2012 - 2013 10 CGPA (School Topper)

TECHNICAL SKILLS



ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS

Citi Gratitude Platinum Award; Citi Gratitude Gold Award ; Citi Gratitude Copper Award

Recognized with exemplary performance awards for reaching the extra mile to deliver in all endeavors by Senior Management

HackBangalore'18

Awarded for the best pitch and idea by Mercedes Benz R&D Germany

School Topper Award

Award for Academic Excellence (School Topper) in 2015

CBSE Certificate of Merit

Awarded for being in top 0.1% of successful candidates in Physics

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Fraud Analytics

- Compared various Supervised Machine Learning techniques like Logistic Regression, Decision Trees, Naive Bayes, Support Vector Machine to detect fraud in publicly available credit card data set
- Published research paper in <u>Springer Nature Singapore</u>

Real Time Face Recognition

Generated training data set of images to build a classifier to Extracted faces from live recognize faces. Extracted faces from live video using HaarCascades Classifier, followed by face recognition using KNN

CERTIFICATIONS

Alteryx Designer Core Certification Alteryx.com

The Complete Introduction to Data Analytics with Tableau

Udemy

POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

CSR - Social Contributor

Successfully led a team of 20+ volunteers to organise Sport Day event for 150+ primary school students in association with New Vision NGO

Tech Head - Annual Literary Fest, DTU

Successfully led a team of 20+ people and created a visually appealing web portal responsible for registration of 1200+ participants